# **Francisco Arriaga Pazos**

4111 Westcity Court, El Paso, TX 79902 - (915) 275 8594 - fran.arrp@gmail.com

Al developer specialized in deep learning and computer vision. My work has focused primarily in generative modeling and recommender systems. A mixed background in mathematics, psychology, and computer science allows me to approach problems with technical rigor without foregoing explainability. I leverage years of experience as an academic researcher as well as a Machine Learning contractor and Statistical Research Analyst for industry

## **SKILLS**

# **Programming languages**

Python
Java
SQL
R

#### **Libraries and Frameworks**

- Pytorch and TensorFlow
- Numpy & Pandas
- OpenCV & SciKit learn
- Docker
- Next Js

## **Spoken Languages**

- Fluent in English and Spanish
- Conversational proficiency in Japanese and French

# **Portfolio:**

Matlab

Github: https://github.com/Blistt

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/francisco-arriaga-pazos/

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant: UTEP, Vision and Learning Lab

El Paso, TX – Jan 2021 – December 2022

- Thesis done on a 2D animation inbetweener using Generative Adversarial Networks and autoencoders with **Pytorch** (Generative Deep Learning AI).
- Pre-processing and supporting functions implemented using Numpy, OpenCV & Sci-Kit Learn.
- Extracted dataset of over 800k triplets (sequence of 3 consecutive frames) directly from scrapped videos using Shot-Detection algorithms.
- Implemented an image retrieval system using pre-trained VGG-19 embeddings with TensorFlow.

Research Assistant: *UTEP, Computer Science and Psychology Departments* 

El Paso, TX – Sept 2017 – June 2018

- Implemented a tv-show and movies recommender system integrating personality scores with Java and Python.
- Created databases and established pipelines for 26 million ratings from over 470,000 users with SQL.
- Implemented a language-based recommender system using a classical vector space model and pre-trained LLM embeddings.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Machine Learning Contractor: MediTrak Life, Inc.

West Lafayette, IN Dec 2023 - Present

- Conceptualized and implemented a system to help regulate blood pressure through behavioral recommendations derived from **XGBoost** regressors.
- Used 3 different augmentation schemes on extremely sparse patient data, and user transfer learning to personalize the recommender algorithm to each user.

Statistical Research Analyst: El Paso Community College

El Paso, TX Jan 2019 – Present

- Maintained and gueried a database of student academic data using SQL.
- Established a data pipeline to automatize reporting processes with Pandas.
- Assisted in the implementation of a district wide change of counseling strategy by providing data driven insights.

## **EDUCATION**

The University of Texas at El Paso (UTEP) The University of Texas at El Paso (UTEP) Master's of Science (MS) in Artificial intelligence Bachelor of Science (BS) in Mathematics & Psychology